Register of the Henry S. Rowen papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Henry S. Rowen papers
1955-2015
2010C6
Hoover Institution Archives
91 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (40.3 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, notes, reports, memoranda, meeting materials, studies, printed matter, photographs, and videorecordings relating to American economic and foreign policy, defenses and military policy, arms control, oil and nuclear energy sources, peaceful nuclear excavation, and the Persian Gulf War.
Rowen, Henry S.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2010, with a large increment received in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at "http://searchworks.stanford.edu/". Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Henry S. Rowen was a senior fellow at the Hoover Institution, a professor of public policy and management emeritus at Stanford University's Graduate School of Business, and a senior fellow emeritus at the Walter H. Shorenstein Asia-Pacific Research Center.
Rowen was born in Boston, Massachusetts on October 11, 1925, and completed a bachelors degree in industrial management at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. He then completed a masters degree in economics at Oxford University in 1955. Rowen was Assistant Director of the U. S. Bureau of the Budget from 1965 to 1966, then president of the RAND Corporation from 1967 to 1972. He was chairman of the National Intelligence Council from 1981 to 1983.
Rowen was Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs in the U. S. Department of Defense from 1989 to 1991, and from 2001 to 2004 he served on the Secretary of Defense Policy Advisory Board. In 2004 and 2005, he served on the Presidential Commission on the Intelligence of the United States Regarding Weapons of Mass Destruction. Rowen was an expert on international security, public policy, economic development, and high-tech industries in the United States and Asia. Rowen passed away in California on November 12, 2015.
Scope and Contents note
The initial acquisition (Boxes 1-4) consists of correspondence, writings, notes, and reports created by Henry S. Rowen, with additional reports, studies, and printed matter relating to peaceful uses of nuclear energy and particularly to nuclear excavation. Most of the materials were created between 1970 and 1975, some of which were created directly for the International Atomic Energy Agency conference of 1975.
Incremental material received in 2016 (Boxes 5-89) is comprised of reports, studies, clippings, and printed matter related to Rowen's work with the Department of Defense and Soviet Union relations, as well as his work at Stanford University, the Hoover Institution, and the Asia-Pacific Research Center focused on public policy and economics. Also includes biographical material, correspondence, photographs, videorecordings, and memorabilia.
2016 Incremental Materials Arrangement Statement
Materials are arranged chronologically, as per Rowen's original order. Due to overlap between Rowen's work in academic and government settings, materials have been separated into career files to facilitate access. Materials related to government agencies, international politics, defense, and nuclear technology have been included in the Department of Defense series. Materials related to Stanford University, the Hoover Institution, the Asia-Pacific Research Center, public policy, and economics have been included in the Stanford series.
United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Economic policy.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Military policy.; Nuclear weapons.; Energy policy--United States.; Petroleum industry and trade.; Nuclear energy.; Persian Gulf War, 1991.; Nuclear excavation.
- Biographical File I, 1975-1976
  Scope and Contents note
  A draft and revised copy of Rowen's research paper The Economics of Peaceful Nuclear Explosions accompanied by handwritten and typed notes.
  - Writings, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Notes, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Personal comments on Gulf Universities Research Consortium (GURC), undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Correspondence I, 1974-1975
  - Sent to Henry Rowen, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Sent to others, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Subject File, 1966-1976
  Subject folders organized by Rowen on topics related to peaceful nuclear explosions, including the use of peaceful nuclear explosions for building and energy purposes, test explosion projects, and politics.
  - Canals, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Harbors, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Economic analysis by others, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Treaties, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Safety, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Arms control and prolifer, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Enjay Chemical Company, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Environment, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Plowshare, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Peaceful Nuclear Explosion Reactor (PACER), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Foreign application, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Oil shale, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Hydrothermal, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Ore leaching, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Progress reports and proposals, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - European trip, 1976 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Gas stimulation, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Writings by Others, 1970-1976
  - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 1974 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - CER Geonuclear Corporation, 1970 October 29 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Elkins, Lloyd E. et al, 1975 April (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Emelynov, V. S., 1973 June (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Fleming, Edward H., 1974 February 27 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Israel, Y. A. et al, 1976 March (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Nordyke, Milo D., 1973-1975 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Otway, Harry J. and Philip D. Pahner, 1976 January (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Panofsky, Wolfgang K. H., 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Roncalio, Teno, 1974 March 12 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Scoville, Herbert Jr., 1974 September (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Unknown, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - White, M., 1975 August 24 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- Printed Matter, 1967-1975
  Reports and publications produced about the peaceful uses of nuclear explosions with analysis of United States and the Soviet Union's research. Notable items include a technical manual for Project Wagon Wheel in Wyoming and the final report for Project PACER in Nevada.
  - Article and clippings, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Project Ketch, 1967 July (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Project Wagon Wheel: Technical Studies Report, 1971 December 31 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Conventional Excavation Methods and Costs for Use in Feasibility Studies of Nuclear and Conventional Earthwork Projects, 1970 March (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Design of a Waterway Connecting the Orinoco and Rio Negro Rivers in the Federal Territory of Amazonas, Venezuela, 1972 June (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Plowshare Technology Assessment Materials Resources Analysis, 1973 January (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - A Review of Soviet Data on the Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Explosions, 1974 April 1 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Project PACER Final Report, 1974 July (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Project PACER Final Report Appendixes, 1974 July (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Peaceful Nuclear Explosions, 1975 April (Box-folder 4: 7)
- 2016 Incremental Materials, 1958-2015
  - Biographical file II, 1982-2013
    Comprised largely of Rowen's business card collection and curriculum vitae. Some business cards were boxed loosely; others were arranged by subject or geographic area. Pictures of the original housing have been included for reference.
    - Short biographical statements, undated (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Oxford certificate, 1987 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - Curriculum vitae, circa 1982, 1989 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Beverly Rowen curriculum vitae, circa 1988 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Washington International Business Council certificate, 1990 January 9 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - RAND Alumni Association certificate, 1993 September (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Stanford University Graduate School of Business certificate, 1993 October (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Oral history transcript, 2010 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - RAND autobiographical interview, 2013 May 28 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - Loose business cards, undated (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - Filed business cards, undated (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - Historical rolodex, undated (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - Rolodex, undated (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Geographic business cards, undated (Box-folder 6: 2-5)
  - Calendars, 1960-2014
    Comprised of calendars and daily planners kept by Rowen from 1960 through 2014.
    - 1960 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - 1961 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 7: 4-5)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 7: 6-7)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 8: 2-3)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 11: 2-3)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 11: 4-5)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 11: 6, 12: 1)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 13: 4-5)
    - Daily schedule, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
      Rowen's daily schedule while working at the Pentagon as Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs from 1989 to 1991. A picture of the original housing has been included for context.
    - 1990 (Box-folder 14: 4, 15: 1)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 15: 2-3)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - 2003 (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - 2004 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - 2005-2006 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - 2007 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - 2008 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - 2009-2010 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - 2011-2012 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - 2013-2014 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Correspondence II, 1960-2003
    Arrangement Statement
    Correspondence was kept in chronological order with only a few descriptive titles, as per Rowen's original order. Additional correspondence was kept separated with other materials and is noted in each subseries.
    - Harvard, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 17: 8)
    - Personal, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 17: 9-10)
    - Personal, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
    - Planning, Programming, Budgeting, 1965 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Personnel, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Vietnam letters, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 5)
      A collection of letters from RAND employees regarding a letter to the New York Times where Daniel Ellsberg, Melvin Gurtov, Oleg Hoeffding, Arnold Horelick, Konrad Kellen, and Paul F. Langer spoke out against the Vietnam War.
    - 1973 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - 1976-1981 (Box-folder 18: 10)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 18: 11)
    - Pan Heuristics, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 18: 12, 19: 1)
    - Beverly Rowen, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - General, 1979 April-June (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - General, 1979 July-September (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - General, 1979 October-December (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - Chau, T., 1979 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - General, 1980 January-March (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - General, 1980 April-August (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - General, 1980 September-December (Box-folder 19: 11)
    - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - National Intelligence Council, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - General, 1981 January-March (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - General, 1981 April-June (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - George P. Shultz, 1982-1983, 1996 (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - Stanford, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 20: 6-7)
    - Uwe Nerlich, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 20: 8-9)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 21: 1-2)
    - Albert Wohlstetter, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 21: 3)
      Note
      See also: Box/Folder 29: 3, 66: 5
    - Aharon Yariv, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 21: 5-7)
    - Imai Ryukichi, 1986 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Hoover Institution, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 22: 3-5)
    - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Pew Memorial Trust, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Li Guoyou, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 22: 9, 23: 1)
    - Israel, 1988 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Norse Hydro, 1988 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Personal/chronological, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - 1991-1994 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - National Interest, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Ca Va Tran, 1994 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - "The Short March,", 1996 (Box-folder 23: 11)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 23: 12)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Sang-Mok Suh, 2003, 2013 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - RAND materials, 1955-2007
    Writings, correspondence, and reports related to Rowen's work at the RAND Corporation. This includes work during his presidency of the company from 1967 through 1972.
    - T. C. Schelling papers, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - "Objectives of the United States Military Posture,", 1959 May 1 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - Writings by others, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 24: 5-6)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box-folder 24: 7)
      See also: Box/folder 21: 3
    - Letters re RAND appointment, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 24: 8-9)
    - Housing and Urban Development, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 24: 10-11)
    - Rowen committee activities, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Systems Analysis Symposium transcript, 1967 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - Speech file #4, 1967 (Box-folder 25: 3-4)
    - Institute for the Study of the Issues of Society (ISIS) proposal, 1967 (Box-folder 25: 5-6)
    - Racism and American Education conference, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 25: 7)
    - Urban programs workshop, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - State Department, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Speech file #5, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 3-4)
    - ITEK Corporation, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 26: 5)
    - Speech file #6, 1969 (Box-folder 26: 6-7)
    - Space task group, 1969 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - Summer study on environmental problems, 1969 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - Union des Industries de la Communauté Européenne, 1969 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - U.S-Japan expert conference, 1969 (Box-folder 27: 4-5)
    - Sixth American German conference, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - Speech file #7, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - Speech file #8, 1971 (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - Leaving RAND, 1971 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - Daniel Ellsberg, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 28: 2)
    - Interview by Jim Digby, circa 1987 (Box-folder 28: 3)
    - History of Henry S. Rowen presidency, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 28: 4)
    - Oversize RAND materials, 1968, 2011 (Box-folder 87: 3)
    - Doctor of Public Policy Honorary Degree, 1993 July 10 (Box 87)
    - Printed matter, 1955-2006 (Box-folder 28: 5, 29: 1)
      Various reports printed by the RAND Corporation on topics such as public policy and RAND history. Also included is Rowen's master's thesis from Oxford in 1955.
    - Wohlstetter, 1958-2007
      Correspondence, writings, and printed matter written and collected by Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter. Rowen worked closely with the Wohlstetters at RAND and later at Pan Heuristics, a security policy consulting firm.
      - Curriculum vitae, circa 1976 (Box-folder 29: 2)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1996 (Box-folder 29: 3)
        See also: Box/Folder 21: 3, 66: 5
      - Wohlstetter testimony, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 29: 4)
      - Festschrift, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 29: 5)
      - Military and defense, 1986 (Box-folder 29: 6)
      - Integrated long-term strategy, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      - Iraq, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 29: 8)
        Contains materials related to Iraq and Operation Desert Storm, also known as Desert Shield or the Gulf War.
      - Balkans, 1993 (Box-folder 29: 9)
      - Balkans, 1994 (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - Balkans, 1995 (Box-folder 30: 2)
      - Albert Wohlstetter in memoriam, 1997 (Box-folder 30: 3)
      - Roberta Wohlstetter writings, 1964, 1984 (Box-folder 30: 4)
      - Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter, 1962-1977 (Box-folder 30: 5)
        A collection of writings co-authored by Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter.
      - "Remembering Roberta Wohlstetter: An Appreciation,", 2007 July 28 (Box-folder 30: 6)
      - Outlines, 1959-1977 (Box-folder 30: 7)
      - Writings, 1961-1992 (Box-folder 30: 8-9, 31: 1-3)
      - "The Delicate Balance of Terror,", 1958 December (Box-folder 31: 4)
      - "Spreading the Bomb without Quite Breaking the Rules,", 1976-1977 (Box-folder 31: 5)
      - Clippings, 1960-1996 (Box-folder 31: 6)
      - Printed matter, 1961-1996 (Boxes 31-32)
  - Department of Defense materials, 1960-2014
    Writings, clippings, reports, and correspondence related to Rowen's work with the Department of Defense and the Defense Policy Board.
    - Arms control by topic, 1960-1981
      A group of writings and reference materials organized together by topic by Rowen.
      - Arms control strategy, 1981, undated (Box-folder 32: 1)
      - Theory and doctrine, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 32: 2)
      - Theory and doctrine, "Arms Race,", 1972-1979 (Box-folder 32: 3)
      - Arms control and space, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 32: 4)
      - Carter, 1977 (Box-folder 32: 5)
      - McNamara, 1964 (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - History, 1960-1979 (Box-folder 33: 2)
      - Anti-ballistic missile debate, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 33: 3)
      - Economic, cost, and budget, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 33: 4)
    - Memoranda, 1960-1988 (Box-folder 33: 5)
    - "Strategic Air Planning and Berlin,", 1961 September 6 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - Speech file #2, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 33: 7-8)
    - Lectures to National Defense College, 1965 February (Box-folder 33: 9)
    - Papers by William (Bill) Kaufmann, 1971 (Box-folder 33: 10)
    - Writings by others, 1971-1989 (Box-folder 33: 11, 34: 1-2)
    - Northern Flank security research, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 34: 3-4)
    - Long Range Research and Development Planning program, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - Notes, 1973, undated (Box-folder 34: 6)
    - Operations Research, Inc. comments, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 7)
    - Skybolt, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 34: 8)
    - SALT Vladivostok Agreement and Kissinger speeches, 1974 (Box-folder 34: 9)
    - SALT statements from others, 1974 (Box-folder 34: 10)
    - SALT news articles, 1974 (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - Aspen summer conference, 1974 (Box-folder 35: 2-3)
    - Writings, 1974 (Box-folder 35: 4)
    - Committee on the Present Danger, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 35: 5-6, 36: 1)
    - Committee on the Present Danger - Nitze, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 36: 2)
    - International Security Affairs - Proliferation, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 36: 3)
    - Ford Administration policy, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 36: 4)
    - Les Aspin on SALT, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 36: 5-6)
    - Cruise missile, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 36: 7-9)
    - Nuclear options, 1975 February-June (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - Bay Area Security Symposium, 1975 October 1 (Box-folder 37: 2)
    - Zumwalt testimony, 1975 December 2 (Box-folder 37: 3)
    - Testimony of Vladivostok agreement, 1975 (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - "Life in a Nuclear Crowd,", 1975 (Box-folder 37: 5)
    - Writings, 1975 (Box-folder 37: 6)
    - SALT and Congress, 1975 (Box-folder 37: 7)
    - SALT statements from others, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 37: 8, 38: 1)
    - SALT news articles, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 38: 2-3)
    - Command and control, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 38: 4)
    - National Security Strategy paper, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - "Japanese-United States Security Ties: The Case for Change,", 1976 December 15 (Box-folder 38: 6)
    - Congressional hearings, 1976 (Box-folder 38: 7)
    - Writings, 1976 (Box-folder 38: 8)
    - "In the Face of Nuclear Proliferation: An Assessment of Policy Options for the United States,", 1976-1977 (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Defense Science Board, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 39: 2)
    - "Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), Fiscal Year 1978 Program for Research and Development,", 1977 February (Box-folder 39: 3)
    - Aspen-New York meeting, 1977 March (Box-folder 39: 4)
    - Writings, 1977 (Box-folder 39: 5-6)
    - SALT statements from others, 1977 (Box-folder 39: 7-8)
    - Wall Street Journal articles written by Rowen, 1977 (Box-folder 39: 9)
    - New York Times articles written by Rowen, 1977 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - SALT articles and editorials, 1977 (Box-folder 40: 2-3)
    - Aspen conference-Berlin meeting, 1977 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Aspen Pacific Security Issues workshop, 1977 (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - Beyond Nuclear Deterrence reviews, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - Defense Nuclear Agency (DNA) New Alternatives Workshop, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 40: 7-9)
    - Modes of defense analysis, 1978 January 9 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - "Middle-East Instabilities and Distant Guarantors (and Disturbers) of the Peace: The Arab-Israeli Case,", 1978 March 6 (Box-folder 40: 11)
    - "The Middle East,", 1978 June 5 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - SALT statements from others, 1978 (Box-folder 41: 2)
    - SALT articles and editorials, 1978 (Box-folder 41: 3)
    - US-Soviet Global Competition talk, 1978 (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - Arms control reference file, 1978 (Box-folder 41: 5)
      A sampling of published works related to arms control used for personal study. Some copies contain marginalia.
    - Writings, 1978 (Box-folder 41: 6)
    - "SALT: Symbolic Politics or Competition with the Russians?,", 1978 (Box-folder 41: 7)
    - "Trade in Arms: Restraint vs. Laissez-Faire,", 1978-1979 (Box-folder 41: 8)
    - Reagan, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - Writings, 1979 (Box-folder 42: 2-3)
    - SALT foreign comment, 1979 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - SALT statements from others, 1979 (Box-folder 42: 5)
    - SALT articles and editorials, 1979 (Box-folder 42: 6-7)
    - Arms control reference file, 1979 (Box-folder 42: 8)
      Published works related to arms control. Most titles are from Foreign Affairs, International Security, and Foreign Policy. Some copies contain marginalia.
    - Wall Street Journal, 1979 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - Writings, 1980 (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - Daedalus, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 43: 3)
    - Clippings, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 43: 4)
      Related to the Soviet Union economy. Articles are written by Rowen and others.
    - M-X missile, 1981 (Box-folder 43: 5)
    - Writings, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 43: 6)
    - Council on Economic Priorities, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 43: 7)
    - Defense Science Board membership, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 43: 8)